const setQ1 = [
    {
    question: "When did Donald Trump begin his second term?",
    answers: ["January 20, 2025", "January 20, 2024",	"June 30, 2025",	"January 21, 2025"], 
    correct: 0,
    explanation: " 20th Amendment: Section 1 of the 20th Amendment, ratified in 1933, specifically sets the end of presidential terms at noon on January 20th." ,
    resource: "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cde7ng85jwgo"
}, 
    {
        question: "What happened on April 21,2025",
        answers: ["Holy Week just ended", "Pope Francis declared who the new pope is", "Pope Francis died", "A new pope got elected"], 
        correct: 2,
        explanation: "Cardinal Kevin Farrell, Camerlengo of the Holy Roman Church, announced the death of Pope Francis." ,
        resource: "https://www.vaticannews.va/en/pope/news/2025-04/pope-francis-dies-on-easter-monday-aged-88.html"
}, 
    {
        question: "Why did the South Korean President declare Martial Law?",
        answers: ["He was on a power trip", "To protect the country from 'antistate forces'", "Because he felt like it", "He was pressured to do so"], 
        correct: 1,
        explanation: "On December 3,  President Yoon Suk Yeol declared martial law, citing the threat of North Korean communist forces and the urgent need to eliminate pro-North, anti-state elements." ,
        resource: "https://www.asiapacific.ca/publication/explainer-yoons-failed-martial-law-decree-future-impacts"
}, 
    {
        question: "Why did the South Korean President get impeached?",
        answers: ["Embezzelment", "Vote Frud", "Corruption", "Abuse of Power"], 
        correct: 3,
        explanation: "The impeachment is a response of the declaration of Martial Law by the President of South Korea, which can be considered an abuse of power." ,
        resource: "https://blogs.loc.gov/law/2024/12/falqs-south-korean-martial-law/"
}, 
    {
        question: "Why did Canadian Prime Minister Mark Carney want the snap election to take place? ",
        answers: ["Amassing power", "Reaction to Trump's Tariff", "Domestic Issues", "Felt like it"], 
        correct: 1,
        explanation: "There are several factors on why the snap election was pushed further but the main reactionary response is the tariff." ,
        resource: "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/crlxe4wxxj4o"
}
]

const setQ2 = [
    {
        question: "What are the dominant major and minor parties in the midterm poll elections?",
        answers: ["Nacionalista Party: dominant majority party, Lakas-CMD: dominant minority party", "Lakas-CMD: subordinate majority party, Nacionalista Party: subordinate minority party.", "Nacionalista Party: dominant majority party, Lakas-CMD: dominant minority party", "Lakas-CMD: dominant majority party, Nacionalista Party: dominant minority party."], 
        correct: 3,
        explanation: "Under Resolution No. 11119, the poll body declares the dominant major and minor parties. " ,
        resource: "https://www.pna.gov.ph/articles/1245516"
}, 
    {
        question: "According to COMELEC, how many Gen Z voters will vote in the 2025 midterm elections?",
        answers: ["About 20 million voters", "About 21 million voters", "About 19 million voters", "About 20 billion voters"], 
        correct: 0,
        explanation: "Generation Z, born in 1997 to 2007, is slowly reaching the age to vote, which explains the high number of voters." ,
        resource: "https://nowyouknowph.rappler.com/1186/gen-z-in-midterm-elections-2025/"
}, 
    {
        question: "When will the 2025 Philippine Senate election take place?",
        answers: ["May 1, 2025", "June 12, 2025", "May 12, 2025", "May 12, 2024"], 
        correct: 2,
        explanation: "It is the given and assigned date for the elections." ,
        resource: "https://www.abs-cbn.com/news/nation/2025/1/9/halalan-2025-key-dates-facts-on-philippines-midterm-elections-1611"
}, 
    {
        question: "What is the full name of COMELEC?",
        answers: ["Cooperation on Elections", "Commerce Election", "Commission on Elections", "Commission on Electives"], 
        correct: 2,
        explanation: "COMELEC is the government orgnization responsible for the ballot." ,
        resource: "https://comelec.gov.ph/?r=home"
}, 
    {
        question: "Why do we use indelible ink, also called electoral ink, when voting?",
        answers: ["For status / posting", "To count the number of people", "To allow double voting.", "To avoid double voting."], 
        correct: 3,
        explanation: "Indelible ink remains in the skin for around 72 and its formula makes it hard to remove by conventional means, making it a good marker." ,
        resource: "https://www.gmanetwork.com/news/lifestyle/content/831051/why-do-we-use-indelible-ink-during-elections/story/"
}
]

const setQ3 = [
    {
        question: "What is former President Duterte's full name?",
        answers: ["Digong 'Rody' Duterte", "D30 Duterte", "Rodrigo Roa Duterte", "Rodrigo Dua Duterte"], 
        correct: 2,
        explanation: "While Rodrigo Duterte is more known as 'Digong', Duterte's full name is Rodrigo Roa Duterte." ,
        resource: "https://www.britannica.com/topic/Rodrigo-Duterte"
}, 
    {
        question: "When was the War on Drugs in the Philippines started?",
        answers: ["June 29, 2016", "June 30, 2016", "July 1, 2016", "June 30, 2017"], 
        correct: 1,
        explanation: "The war on drugs started as soon as Rodrigo Duterte took office, which is June 30." ,
        resource: "https://www.hrw.org/tag/philippines-war-drugs"
}, 
    {
        question: "Who has Rodrigo Duterte in custody?",
        answers: ["International Criminal Court (ICC)", "Intentional Criminal Court (ICC)", "International Criminal Council (ICC)", "International College Court (ICC)"], 
        correct: 0,
        explanation: "The International Criminal Court (ICC) investigates and, where warranted, tries individuals charged with the gravest crimes of concern to the international community: genocide, war crimes, crimes against humanity and the crime of aggression." ,
        resource: "https://www.icc-cpi.int/about/the-court"
}, 
    {
        question: "What was the major charge against Rodrigo Duterte?",
        answers: ["Crimes against Humanity of corruption", "Crimes against Humanity of taking drugs", "Crimes against Humanity of kidnapping and torture", "Crimes against Humanity of murder, torture, and rape"], 
        correct: 3,
        explanation: "This was the result of the DDS (Davao Death Squad) and the attacks were systematic." ,
        resource: "https://www.icc-cpi.int/news/situation-philippines-rodrigo-roa-duterte-icc-custody"
}, 
    {
        question: "Where was Rodrigo Duterte taken?",
        answers: ["The Hague in the Netherlands", "The windmill in the Netherlands", "The Hague in Russia", "The Hague with the Dutch"], 
        correct: 0,
        explanation: "According to the official site, the ICC's headquarters is in Hague, Netherlands." ,
        resource: "https://www.icc-cpi.int/about/the-court"
}
]

const setQ4 = [
    {
        question: "Why was the 2025 Philippine budget controversal?",
        answers: ["Massive cuts to education, health and calamity response", "Increased Military Spending", "Pork Barrel Scam", "Corruption"], 
        correct: 0,
        explanation: "" ,
        resource: "https://thedefiant.net/the-2025-budget-controversy-highlights-filipino-politicians-continued-reliance-on-patronage-politics/"
}, 
    {
        question: "What is the major cause of inflation in the Philippines?",
        answers: ["Corruption", "Tarrifs", "Wars", "Supply and Demand"], 
        correct: 3,
        explanation: "While policies can change inflation rates, supply and demand are the main core of the economic cycles." ,
        resource: "https://amro-asia.org/addressing-high-inflation-in-the-philippines-the-role-of-policy-mix"
}, 
    {
        question: "What is the major cause of unemployment in the Philippines?",
        answers: ["Economic instability", "Nepotism and cronyism", "Rapid population growth and insufficient job creations", "Corruption and a mismatch between skills and job requirement"], 
        correct: 2,
        explanation: "The mismatch of the rapid population growth and insufficient job creations leave a gap which leads to a gap in employment, leading to unemployment." ,
        resource: "https://www.imf.org/external/pubs/ft/wp/2002/wp0223.pdf"
}, 
    {
        question: "According to PSA, what is the projected population of the Philippines on 2055?",
        answers: ["138.67 Million", "138.69 Million", "139.67 Million", "138.67 Billion"], 
        correct: 0,
        explanation: "This is according to the predictions of the Philippine Statistics Authority. There are more predictions but this is in scenario 2." ,
        resource: "https://psa.gov.ph/content/philippine-population-projected-be-around-13867-million-2055-under-scenario-2"
}, 
    {
        question: "What is the Philippines' rank in the GDP index?",
        answers: ["1", "33", "75", "181"], 
        correct: 1,
        explanation: "This is the ranking based on the most recent value of the GDP indicators in the world bank's official website." ,
        resource: "https://data.worldbank.org/indicator/NY.GDP.MKTP.CD?most_recent_value_desc=true"
}
]